<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Intro to Social Data Science</title>
    <link>https://isdsucph.github.io/isds2022/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Intro to Social Data Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>abn@sodas.ku.dk (Andreas Bjerre-Nielsen)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>abn@sodas.ku.dk (Andreas Bjerre-Nielsen)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://isdsucph.github.io/isds2022/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Timeplan</title>
      <link>https://isdsucph.github.io/isds2022/page/timeplan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>abn@sodas.ku.dk (Andreas Bjerre-Nielsen)</author>
      <guid>https://isdsucph.github.io/isds2022/page/timeplan/</guid>
      <description>This page contains a schedule of the teaching sessions. Most of the teaching will take place August 01-12, 2022, with additional supervision on August 16. Each day will generally contain one-two teaching sessions. Most sessions will follow the daily schedule below:
Morning session (9-12): 9-10 Live lecture, 10-12 Notebook with integrated lecturing videos on technical aspects of the session + exercises Lunch break (12-13): Afternoon session (13-16): 13-14 Live lecture, 14-16 Notebook with integrated lecturing videos on technical aspects of the session + exercises Office hour, optional: 16-17 (booking system through Google Sheets, see link in the schedule below) The complete schedule of sessions is listed below with title, lecturer and links to material.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installation</title>
      <link>https://isdsucph.github.io/isds2022/post/install/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>abn@sodas.ku.dk (Andreas Bjerre-Nielsen)</author>
      <guid>https://isdsucph.github.io/isds2022/post/install/</guid>
      <description>This class will involve a lot of coding, for which you will need some basic tools.
Python, Jupyter Notebook and JupyterLab A git client A github account We will discuss these tools in much more detail in class, so don&amp;rsquo;t worry if this is all new and perhaps a bit frightening right now.
Python, Jupyter Notebook and JupyterLab Python is a free programming language. We will use the distribution called Anaconda as it comes with the most essential for working with data, statistical computing and visualizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparation</title>
      <link>https://isdsucph.github.io/isds2022/post/preparation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>abn@sodas.ku.dk (Andreas Bjerre-Nielsen)</author>
      <guid>https://isdsucph.github.io/isds2022/post/preparation/</guid>
      <description>Guide to preparations It is necessary that you time preparing for the course. We expect that you have spent up 50 hours on learning basic Python and pandas before we begin teaching, depending on your prior experience. In particular you should do the following (prioritized order):
Install anaconda and other software Open the Assignment 0 notebook, see this guide on how to open and use a notebook Work on Assignment 0 - try to solve as much as possible When you get stuck then follow the trouble shooting guideline below - start with a) and move to d) Assignment 0 In preparation for the course you are expected to hand in an assignment in Python before lectures begin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignments</title>
      <link>https://isdsucph.github.io/isds2022/post/assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>abn@sodas.ku.dk (Andreas Bjerre-Nielsen)</author>
      <guid>https://isdsucph.github.io/isds2022/post/assignment/</guid>
      <description>This post contain practical information related to each of the three assignments. Check back later for news about deadlines and other assignment related information. All assignments must be handed via Absalon here.
Assignment 0: Available June 28. Deadline July 28 @ 12.00
Assignment 1: Available August 3. Deadline August 5 @ 23.59
Assignment 2: Available August 9. Deadline August 12 @ 23.59</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course readings</title>
      <link>https://isdsucph.github.io/isds2022/page/readings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>abn@sodas.ku.dk (Andreas Bjerre-Nielsen)</author>
      <guid>https://isdsucph.github.io/isds2022/page/readings/</guid>
      <description>Textbook for general introduction to social data science:
Big by Bit - Social research in the digital age by Matthew J. Salganik [BBB], free online version here. Textbooks for data science in Python
Python for Data Analysis, 3rd ed. (2022) by Wes McKinney [PDA] Python Machine Learning, 3rd ed. (2019) by Sebastian Raschka &amp;amp; Vahid Mirjalili [PML] Preparation and Assignment 0 The course begin with your preparation for the teaching. This consists in Assignment 0 which is a learning module and assignment together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exam project</title>
      <link>https://isdsucph.github.io/isds2022/post/exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>abn@sodas.ku.dk (Andreas Bjerre-Nielsen)</author>
      <guid>https://isdsucph.github.io/isds2022/post/exam/</guid>
      <description>When the teaching in our course finishes you are to hand in a project. The formal requirements are found here along with details on grading. The exam period runs until August 23 at 10 AM.
In this blog post we want to expand a little bit on how a good project will look. The focus of the project is to pose and interesting question to data that can be collected publicly and attempt to answer it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical info</title>
      <link>https://isdsucph.github.io/isds2022/page/practical/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>abn@sodas.ku.dk (Andreas Bjerre-Nielsen)</author>
      <guid>https://isdsucph.github.io/isds2022/page/practical/</guid>
      <description>This page contains information about the course groups as well as information on mandatory assignments and exam project.
Place and time The course runs from August 1, 2022 to August 23. See timeplan for teaching schedule.
All lectures and lab/exercise classes on campus will take place in CSS 35-01-05. Groups You have two options of being assigned to a group. The first is that you report the group to us and where all members consent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful Jupyter tips</title>
      <link>https://isdsucph.github.io/isds2022/post/jupyter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>abn@sodas.ku.dk (Andreas Bjerre-Nielsen)</author>
      <guid>https://isdsucph.github.io/isds2022/post/jupyter/</guid>
      <description>This post provides a short intro on picking up useful Jupyter hacks. We begin with a short overview of the most essential Jupyter shortcuts and skills. If you have not read the introduction to Jupyter you should do that immediately, see here.
Keyboard short cuts Editing and executing cells
enter edit mode: click inside the cell or press ENTR exit edit mode: click outside cell or press ESC. executing code within a cell is SHFT+ENTR or CTRL+ENTR (not same!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
